A Guide to the Alexander Gordon Bearn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA007
Rockefeller Archive Center
Alexander Gordon Bearn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1951-1988
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Bearn, Alexander G.
FA007
21.12 Cubic Feet 48 document boxes.
48 document boxes.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 B38
Arrangement note
Arranged into three series:
Series 1: Laboratory Notebooks. Series 2: Correspondence. Series 3: Subject Files: Organizations.
Correspondence and subject files arranged alphabetically.
Biographical/Historical note
Alexander G. Bearn (1923-), a physician and scientist, was affiliated with the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research starting in 1951. Prior to that he was a house physician at Guy's Hospital (1946-1947) and house physician in the Postgraduate Medical School (1948-1951), both in London. Subsequently, after joining the staff of RIMR, he was an associate professor (1957-1964) and then professor and senior physician (1964-1966). In 1966, he accepted the position of professor of medicine at Cornell University where he was the chairman of the department of medicine until 1977. During this period, he was physician-in-chief of New York Hospital.
Dr. Bearn has also served as a trustee of the Rockefeller University and the Helen Hay Whitney Foundation, a member of the board of scientific counselors of Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center and the National Institute of Arthritis, Metabolism and Digestive Diseases. Bearn also served as president of the Royal Society of Medicine Foundation, Inc.
Conditions Governing Access note
Collection is open for scholarly research, with select files restricted as noted.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Boxes 1-3 were officially ingested as Accession 1990:019. All other materials were subsequent addtions to the collection.
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Bearn, Alexander G.
- Laboratory Notebooks, 1
  - CU++ #1, 1951 November 10-1952 February 2 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #2, 1951 April 2-June 10 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #3, 1952 May 19-June 9 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #3A, 1952 May 26-December 2 (Box 1)
  - Cu++ #4, 1952 December 5-1953 June 8 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #5, 1953 September 18-1954 May 6 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #6, 1954 May 11-December 28 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #7, 1955 January 12-June 16 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #8, 1955 June 20-1956 July 31 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #9, 1956 September 14-1957 May 9 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #10, 1957 April 27-1958 March 12 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #11, 1958 March 18-1958 December 15 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #12, 1958 December 22-1959 July 27 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #13, 1959 August-1961 November 21 (Box 1)
  - CU++ #14, 1962 January 6-1964 January 13 (Box 1)
  - Direct Reacting Copper, 1955 September (Box 1)
  - Starch Blocks, 1959 October (Box 1)
  - Starch Blocks, 1960 September (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1957 May (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1957 October (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1958 January (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1958 April (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1958 October (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1959 August (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1961 September (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1962 August (Box 1)
  - Starch Gels, 1965 January (Box 1)
  - Gels & Starch Blocks #1, 1962 October 16-1964 January 9 (Box 1)
  - Gels & Starch Blocks #2, 1964 January 14-1964 April 29 (Box 1)
  - Acrylamide Gels, undated (Box 1)
  - CP (Na CN) #1, 1957 July 18-1958 June 11 (Box 2)
  - CP (Na CN) #2, 1958 June 16-1958 December 29 (Box 2)
  - CP (Na CN) #3, 1959 January 2-1959 July 7 (Box 2)
  - CP (Na CN) #4, 1959 July 27-1959 September 21 (Box 2)
  - CP (Enzyme) #1, 1952 January 3-1956 December 7 (Box 2)
  - CP (Enzyme) #2, 1956 December 11-1958 April 5 (Box 2)
  - CP (Enzyme) #3, 1958 April 11-1958 December 30 (Box 2)
  - CP (Enzyme) #4, 1959 January 6-1959 July 30 (Box 2)
  - Complement #1, 1961 April-May (Box 2)
  - Complement, 1961 August 16-1962 April 4 (Box 2)
  - Complement, 1961 September 22-1962 August 23 (Box 2)
  - Paper Electrophoresis, 1959 November 30 (Box 2)
  - Paper Electrophoresis, undated (Box 2)
  - Paper Electrophoresis, undated (Box 2)
  - Immunoelecthophoresis, undated (Box 2)
  - Hemolysates Bank #1 (Box 2)
  - Carbonic Anhydrase & Starch Blocks, 1959 January (Box 2)
  - Carbonic Anhydrase, 1959 August 4 (Box 2)
  - Catalase, 1959 December 14 (Box 2)
  - Alpha 2, 1956 July 6 (Box 2)
  - Alpha 2, 1957 August 7 (Box 2)
  - Alpha 2, 1958 May 5 (Box 2)
  - Alpha-Amino-Nitrogen, 1957 October 24 (Box 2)
  - ZN++ #1, 1954 November (Box 2)
  - ZN++ #2, 1956 June 5 (Box 2)
  - ZN++ #3, 1960 January 25 (Box 2)
  - Procedures (Susan?), 1961 July (Box 3)
  - Transfer Stock, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Photography, 1962 March 6-23 (Box 3)
  - P.H. Kammeyer, 1960 September 7-December 19 (Box 3)
  - P.H. Kammeyer, 1960 December 21 (Box 3)
  - Lowell Goldsmith, 1960 Summer (Box 3)
  - Glutathlone Analysis, 1957 July (Box 3)
  - Cellulose Acetate-Dr. Kirk, Betsy (Allawany?), 1962 September (Box 3)
  - C.R. Paylingwright, Haptoglobins, 1961 October 7 (Box 3)
  - Prematurity, 1961 December-1962 August 28 (Box 3)
  - Normal Sera and Normal Families, undated (Box 3)
  - Lab Order Book, 1959 November (Box 3)
  - Dr Elliot Vesell, 1960 July 7-September (Box 3)
  - Dr E. Vesell Book 2, 1960 September 14 (Box 3)
  - Dr E. S. Vesell Hospital 701 Boo 3, 1961 April 3 (Box 3)
  - E. Vesell, Book 4, 1961 August 20 (Box 3)
  - Elliot Vesell Book 5, 1961 October 9 (Box 3)
  - Dr Vesell (Ellen) Scrap Notebook, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Phoebe Mason Methods, Solution, and Graphs, 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - Stone, undated (Box 3)
  - Statistics-Notes, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Statistics-Calculations, undated (Box 3)
  - Ceruloplasmin #I, 1959 September (Box 3)
  - Ceruloplasmin #II, 1960 June-1961 April (Box 3)
  - Ceruloplasmin #3, 1961 September (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 2
  - A, 1969-1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - B, 1966-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - B, 1977-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - B, 1977-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3A)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted from scholarly research.
  - B, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - B, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1A)
  - B, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - B, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 2A)
  - C, 1964-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - C, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - C, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1A)
  - C, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - D, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - D, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 3A)
  - D, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - D, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4A)
  - E, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - E, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 1A)
  - F, 1967-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - F, 1967-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2A)
  - F, 1967-1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - F, 1967-1982 (Box 7, Folder 3A)
  - G, 1966-1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - G, 1966-1976 (Box 8, Folder 1A)
  - G, 1977-1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - G, 1977-1982 (Box 8, Folder 2A)
  - H, 1966-1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - H, 1966-1976 (Box 8, Folder 3A)
  - H, 1966-1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - H, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - H, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - H, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 3A)
  - I, 1967-1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - J, 1967-1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - J, 1967-1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - J, 1967-1982 (Box 10, Folder 2A)
  - K, 1966-1982 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - K, 1966-1982 (Box 10, Folder 3A)
  - K, 1966-1982 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - K, 1966-1982 (Box 10, Folder 4A)
  - L, 1966-1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - L, 1966-1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - L, 1966-1982 (Box 11, Folder 2A)
  - L, 1966-1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - L, 1966-1976 (Box 11, Folder 3A)
  - M, 1966-1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - M, 1967-1977 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - M, 1967-1977 (Box 12, Folder 1A)
  - M, 1966-1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - M, 1977-1982 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - M, 1977-1982 (Box 12, Folder 3A)
  - M, 1977-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - M, 1977-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1A)
  - N, 1966-1982 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - N, 1966-1982 (Box 13, Folder 2A)
  - N, 1966-1982 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - O, 1966-1982 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - O, 1966-1982 (Box 13, Folder 4A)
  - P, 1967-1976 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - P, 1967-1976 (Box 14, Folder 1A)
  - P, 1977-1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - P, 1977-1982 (Box 14, Folder 2A)
  - R, 1970-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - R, 1970-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3A)
  - R, 1970-1982 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - R, 1970-1982 (Box 15, Folder 1A)
  - S, 1970-1976 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - S, 1970-1976 (Box 15, Folder 2A)
  - S, 1977-1982 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - S, 1977-1982 (Box 15, Folder 3A)
  - S, 1977-1982 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - S, 1977-1982 (Box 15, Folder 4A)
  - T, 1966-1976 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - T, 1966-1976 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - T, 1966-1976 (Box 16, Folder 2A)
  - T, 1977-1982 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - T, 1977-1982 (Box 16, Folder 3A)
  - V, 1958-1976 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - V, 1958-1976 (Box 16, Folder 4A)
  - V, 1958-1976 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - V, 1958-1976 (Box 16, Folder 5A)
  - W, 1966-1976 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - W, 1966-1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - W, 1977-1982 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - W, 1977-1982 (Box 17, Folder 3A)
  - W, 1977-1982 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - W, 1977-1982 (Box 17, Folder 4A)
- Subject Files: Organizations, 3
  - Association of American Physicians (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Association of American Physicians (Box 18, Folder 1A)
  - Association of Physicians of Great Britain and Ireland (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The American Society of Human Genetics (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - The American Society of Human Genetics (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - The American Society of Human Genetics - Committees (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - The Association of American Medical Colleges (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - American Cancer Society (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - American Society for Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - American Society for Clinical Investigation (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - American Society for Clinical Investigation (Box 20, Folder 1A)
  - American College of Physicians (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - American College of Physicians Course NYH, 1978 January 9-13 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - American Geriatrics Society, Inc. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - American Hospital of Paris (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - American Bureau for Medical Advancement in China (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - American Federation for Clinical Research (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - American College of Clinical Pharmacology (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - American College of Physicians (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - American College of Physicians (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - American College of Physicians (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - American College of Physicians (Box 22, Folder 2A)
  - British Schools and Universities Foundation (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Biological Sciences Curriculum Study (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Century Association - General (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Century Association - General (Box 22, Folder 5A)
  - Century Association - Admissions (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Corporation (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Center for the Study of Drug Development (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Columbia Medical Society (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Council on Foundations, Inc. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Community Treatment Foundation (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - CIBA Foundation - Meeting and Paper - London, 1979 January (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - The CIBA Foundation (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - English Speaking Union (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - English Speaking Union (Box 24, Folder 3A)
  - The Epsomian Society (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Fulbright Alumni Association (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Genetics Society of America, Inc. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Grand Rounds (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The Grolier Club (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - The Grolier Club (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - The Grolier Club (Box 25, Folder 3A)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Gutherie Clinic (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Hahnemann Medical College and Hospital of Philadelphia (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Harvey Society (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Harvey Society (Box 26, Folder 2A)
  - Health Action International (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Heberden Medical History Society (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Health Research Council of New York City (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Hotel Okura - Japan (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Iran Trip (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Iran Trip (Box 27, Folder 1A)
  - Iran Feasibility Study Group (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - International Section of the Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Industrial Sector Liaison Group (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Interurban Clinical Club (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Irvington House Institute (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Irvington House Institute (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - The Jackson Laboratory (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - The Jackson Laboratory (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - The Jackson Laboratory - Minutes of Meeting (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - The Jackson Laboratory Misc. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - The Jackson Laboratory Misc. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - The Jackson Laboratory - Board of Trustees (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Javeriana University (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - The Journal of the American Medical Association (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Knickerbocker Club (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Knickerbocker Club (Box 30, Folder 6A)
  - Albert and Mary Lasker Foundation (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Albert and Mary Lasker Foundation 1 (Nominations) (Box 31, Folder 1A)
  - The Lindsley F. Kimball Research Institute (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation - General, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation - General, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 3A)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation - Psychiatry, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation - Psychiatry, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 3A)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation - Psychiatry, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation - Psychiatry, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - V.D. Mattia Lectureship (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - METPAK, Ltd. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - METPAK, Ltd. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Mexican Foundation for Health (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Milton Helpern Library of Legal Medicine (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - The Medical Society of London (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Medical Research Council (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Medical Research Society (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - The New York Medical and Surgical Society (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - The National Foundation New York Chapter (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - National Genetics Foundation Proposal (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - New York Academy of Sciences (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - New York Blood Center (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - New York Blood Center (Box 36, Folder 2A)
  - Old Epsomian Club (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Practitioners (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Practitioners (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Royal College of Physicians, 1982-1984 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Royal College of Physicians, 1982-1984 (Box 37, Folder 1A)
  - Royal College of Physicians, 1959-1982 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Royal College of Physicians, 1959-1982 (Box 37, Folder 2A)
  - Royal College of Physicians, 1984-1988 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Royal College of Physicians, 1984-1988 (Box 38, Folder 1A)
  - Royal College of Physicians, 1984-1988 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Royal Postgraduate Medical School (Hammersmith Hospital) (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation I (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation I (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation II (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation II (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation II (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation III (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation III (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation IV (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Committee on the Radiation Effects Research Foundation (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation - Research Program Plan Draft, 1986 March (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation - The Thirteenth Meeting of the Scientific Council (March 18-20) (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation - The Fourteenth Meeting of the Scientific Council (March 17-20) (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Radiation Effects Research Foundation Program - Project Budget Proposal (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine Foundation (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine Foundation (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine Foundation (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine Foundation (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine Foundation (Box 43, Folder 1A)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 44, Folder 1A)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 44, Folder 2A)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 45, Folder 3A)
  - Royal College of Physicians and The Royal Society of Medicine (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine - Nominee Information (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - The Royal Society of Medicine - Nominee Information (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Sigma Tau (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - St. Andrew's Society of New York State (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Stanton Griffis Lectures, 1979-1980 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Stanton Griffis Lectures, 1979-1980 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Scripps Clinic (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - University of Texas Medical Branch - Galveston (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - The Welcome Trust (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Woodrow Wilson Visiting Fellowships (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Worshipful Society of Apothecaries of London (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - World Health Organization (Box 48, Folder 3)